

Profile

Dedicated and experienced Flutter developer with over three years working as a mobile software developer. Adept in building mobile apps with the Flutter framework for Android and IOS, while providing back-end services like authentication, and cloud storage with Firebase and SQLite. Committed to working with organizations to accelerate growth with efficient and up-to-date technology.

Links

Github

https://github.com/thenifemi

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nifemii

Employment History

Web Development Intern at NCK Tech, Lagos

July 2018 — September 2018

- Created web-based promotional content for different campaigns, optimized home, and landing pages, designed and developed in-home productivity applications with JavaScript.
- Organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.

Mobile Developer at NullBug, Francisco Beltrao

December 2020 — Present

- Built scalable mobile applications for Android and iOS with the Flutter framework, optimized applications for efficiency and speed.
- Developed enterprise mobility apps for organizations utilizing a lot of Native platform features.
- Worked well independently and on a team to solve problems.
- Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.

Freelance Mobile Developer, Blumenau

March 2020 — Present

- Provided superior customer service to clients by addressing all questions and concerns.
- Built diverse applications like e-commerce apps, games, and other simpler apps for clients.

Education

Software Engineering, National Institute of Information and Technology, Lagos

December 2016 — January 2019

Details

R. Ayres Gama, 222 - Centro Blumenau, 89012-480 Brazil +55 47 984340408 thenifemi@gmail.com

Skills

Flutter

Android

iOS

Java

SOL

Firebase

Kotlin

Languages

English

Portuguese

Hobbies

Walking, Running, Reading, Binge-watching, and overthinking.

Projects

Pet Shop

Pet Shop is an e-commerce application for Android and iOS built with Flutter. Implemented the Flutter framework for large-scale Android and iOS applications, implementing native platform features like camera accessibility and location reading.

https://github.com/thenifemi/petShop

- · Provider with MVC architecture
- Firebase services (authentication, Firebase Firestore, cloud functions)
- API (Google places API)
- Open-source

Moving Pictures

Real-world movie database mobile application with the Flutter SDK, DDD clean architecture, and scalable BLOC architecture.

https://github.com/thenifemi/movingPictures

- BLOC with DDD clean architecture
- REST API
- Dependency Injection
- Firebase services (authentication, firestore, cloud functions)
- Open-source

Jottr

Jottr is a note-taking application for Android and iOS built with Flutter. Implemented the Flutter framework for large-scale Android and iOS applications.

https://github.com/thenifemi/jottr

- · BLOC with DDD clean architecture
- Firebase services (authentication, firestore, cloud functions)
- · Open-source

Vox Populi

Vox Populi is a news application for Android and iOS built with Flutter. BLOC and DDD clean architecture were implemented in this project and other open-source libraries.

https://github.com/thenifemi/vox-populi

- · BLOC with DDD clean architecture
- REST API (NewsApi.org)
- Dependency Injection